

Controls Engineer | Software Developer

Natick, MA | (502) 295-8499

hassan.mcginnis@gmail.com hrmcginnis.github.io

Summary

I'm an engineer with professional software development and test experience using MATLAB, Simulink, and C++, as well as research experience in robust control and signal processing for structural vibration analysis.

Software Skills

Tools/Environments: MATLAB, Simulink, Stateflow, GNU/Linux, Emacs

Languages: MATLAB, C++, bash, python

Work Experience

MedAcuity Software | Software Specialist | Westford, MA

July 2017 - present

 Software consultant for clients in the medical device industry, serving as the domain expert with MATLAB and Simulink test and development.

MathWorks | Senior Application Engineer (Post-sales) | Natick, MA

Sept 2013 - July 2016

- As a domain expert in Simulink code generation workflows, provided solutions for major customers using Simulink Coder and Embedded Coder for production C/C++ code generation.
- Developed/advocated for software improvements for MATLAB and Simulink based on customer needs, including achievement of MISRA compliant code, enhanced user customization of generated code, and improved support for thirdparty compilers.

Projects

MedAcuity Software | Verification of Controls Software for Surgical Robot

Aug 2017 - present

- Developed a comprehensive strategy for verification and full MC/DC test coverage of Simulink-based state machines and control algorithms governing robotic arm motion.
- Lead a team of engineers through verification of over 400 functional and nonfunctional software requirements implemented in Simulink, C++, and MATLAB code.
- Collaborated with a third-party software vendor to unit test custom software that enables Simulink code generation and compilation for the QNX Neutrino realtime operating system.

MathWorks | Development of Python System Object for Simulink Raspberry Pi Support Package

May 2016

- Developed a Simulink block in MATLAB and C for the Raspberry Pi support package that interfaces with the Python/C API, allowing users to easily send simulation data to any Python module on the Raspberry Pi in soft real-time.
- Demonstrated the functionality by using Simulink to drive a servomotor with a Raspberry Pi using the RaspiRobot Python library.

Purdue University | Sensitivity analysis of wear prognosis in an H_{∞} controlled F-16 simulation

Aug 2010 - Dec 2011

- Investigated the minimization of fault propagation in a hydraulic actuator through real-time adjustment in the commanded flight path.
- Developed a robust altitude controller for an F-16 fighter aircraft model using H_{∞} synthesis.
- Performed sensitivity analysis of the path adjustment algorithm under modeling error.
- Demonstrated the improved control strategy using a hydraulic solenoid valve hardware-in-the-loop system prototyped in Simulink and driven by dSPACE software.

Education

Purdue University

MS Mechanical Engineering | 3.81/4.00 | Dec 2011

University of Kentucky

BS Mechanical Engineering | 3.46/4.00 | May 2009